#### Contact

60192797122 (Mobile) mohdazlan.abas@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ mohdazlanabas (LinkedIn) github.com/mohdazlanabas (Portfolio)

### Top Skills

Strategy
Change Management
Business Strategy

### Languages

Indonesian (Full Professional)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Malay (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

ISO 14000 Lead Auditor
Open Water Diver
NLP Practitioner
ASEAN Certified Professional
Engineer
Ceritified Energy Auditor

# **Azlan Abas**

Technologist, Practitioner, Consultant Ubud

# Summary

Clubhouse @mohdazlanabas, Coffeepreneur, Century Rider, Marathon Runner, Skater, Diver, Photographer, Rope Jumper, Engineer. Extensive experience in South East Asia and a well rounded experience in Business, Operations, Engineering and Project Management.

Currently residing in Bali for a year to reset and focus on increasing deeper knowledge of a technology area. Has passion in Startups, Innovation and Value Creation. Works and assist large size and Small Medium Enterprise organisations to achieve business excellence by merging experiences in the technical and commercial area, from strategy to engineering to business to operations.

In terms of credentials, being an Asean Chartered Professional Engineer, Professionally certified in (Mechanical Engineering, Project Management), USGBC LEED AP, Kaizen, Lean, Six Sigma, ISO 9000, ISO 14000, ISO 45000, Energy Auditing, Neuro Linguistic Programming (EFT, TLT, Hypnotherapy) MBA in Finance and Degree in Mechanical Engineering among others.

In terms of experience, Azlan served in UEM Edgenta, KFM Holdings, Petronas, AmBank, General Electric, 3M Company, Bechtel Corporation, Proton Malaysia & Gas Malaysia. His specialty covers Mechanical Engineering, Operational Excellence, Project Management, Corporate Strategy, Business Development, Organisational Development, Mergers Acquisition & Integration, Investor Relations.

Past engagements allowed him to be in several market sectors such as Oil & Gas, Automotive, Consumer Retail, Government Business, Facility Mangement, Construction, Power, Manufacturing, Property, Healthcare, Banking.

# Experience

AG Alchemy Sdn Bhd Principal Consultant January 2009 - Present (13 years) Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Own and provide technical expertise via consultation on M&E & C&S Consultancy, Project Management and LEAN Six Sigma to clients as a Professional Consultant. The company is a Malaysian Registered SPAN Competent Company and a Malaysian Registered Professional Engineering Company. This is a Professional Engineering services company covering building, road, bridge, STP project scope in Malaysia. Kept a part time role to maintain hours for upkeep of various technical certifications.

#### Freelance

Blockchain Technology, Economics/Tokenomics, Smart Contracts, Crypto Currency Learner & Practitioner September 2020 - August 2021 (1 year)

Blockchain Technology, Coding, Economics/Tokenomics, Smart Contracts, Crypto Currency, Learner & Practitioner. Brushed up on HTML, CSS, Javasript, Java, React, Phyton, Solidity. Took tie of to pursue passion in learning about technology.

Kuwait Oil Company- AlGhanim Project Development Specialist- MENA September 2019 - August 2020 (1 year) Kuwait

Cover the full spectrum of a large scale major Crude Oil pipeline project from Project Planning, Project Costing to Project Execution and Budget Control, Claims, Client and Stakeholder Communication, Contract Management, Project Flnancial Close. A full PMBOK and Kuwait Oil Company process and procedure was executed with international group of team. Represented Malaysian company fully as Project Director and representative.

UEM Edgenta Berhad COO, Property & Facilities Division August 2018 - July 2019 (1 year) Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Oversee all aspects of UEM Edgenta Berhad Properties & Facilities Division operations and business development activities. Property Management and Facility Management. Design, Build and Retrofit of Buildings for certification

towards LEEDs/GBI, Energy Efficient Building Solution such as Chiller on EPC model and CoGen, Renewable Energy for Building NEM, Integrated Building Management Systems, Building M&E Contracting, All solutions delivered up to IOT level operations for clients. Full PnL responsibility achieving above 20% YoY revenue growth.

KFM Holdings Sdn Bhd Vice President Corporate Development January 2014 - June 2018 (4 years 6 months) Level 14, Amfirst Building, SS 7/15, Kelana Jaya, 57301 PJ

Heading Corporate Strategy and M&A role that is in position to grow the company through non-organic growth. My role is to also manage and strategise and manage corporate services area such as HR, Admin, IT, Communications, Business Development, Marketing and Corporate Planning and Corporate Finance. PnL responsibility. Managing Key Accounts and Business Development. Achieve 18% CAGR growth over period.

#### **PETRONAS**

3 years

Head, Mergers, Acquisitions, Integration, Petronas Dagangan Berhad June 2012 - November 2013 (1 year 6 months)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Creating business growth through ventures in Philippines, Thailand and Vietnam by designing and having oversight of infrastructure installation for a fully operative and integrated South East Asia Region operations covering the whole operating components of an organization from back end to front end including business, corporate and organizational strategy development and implementation.

Head, Business & Operations Performance and Change Management, Petronas Dagangan Berhad December 2010 - May 2012 (1 year 6 months)

Value creation and addition to the organization via leadership, strategy, planning, managing, decision making, steering, directing, organizing, communicating, innovating, improving, developing all types of resources that best fits the purpose to shareholders and stakeholders.

AmBank Group Head, Business and Operations Strategy January 2009 - December 2010 (2 years) Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia IT Transformation- Developed banks new Mid Term and Long Term (15 Years) strategy consisting of Core Banking replacement, organization re-design, process innovation. Led a team of Business and IT specialist in the biggest revamp done in the organization.

#### General Electric

S.E.A Regional Development Manager January 2004 - December 2008 (5 years)

Lean Six Sigma, Asia market penetration, business strategy and development, product management, distribution channel management, compliance and regulation, operations management, risk management, overall country business covering industrial and retails market

#### 3M

Sales & Marketing Manager January 2002 - December 2003 (2 years)

P&L management and growth, sales and marketing management, government relations, government advisory on directions relating to consumer and industrial products used in Malaysia, Key Account Management, Retail Sales, Government Sales.

#### **Bechtel**

Senior Buyer January 2000 - December 2001 (2 years)

Procurement scope covering purchasing, logistics, expediting, warehousing, tendering South East Asia projects. Managing teams in delivering products from fabrication/manufacturing to construction and commissioning, Negotiations, contract management.

#### Proton

Production Engineer
January 1999 - December 1999 (1 year)

Production Engineering, Production Design and Planning, Robotics, Technology Sourcing and Transfer, Engineering Design, Plant Engineering, Construction and Commissioning.

Gas Malaysia Sdn Bhd Project Engineer January 1996 - December 1996 (1 year) Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia Project Management, Construction Management, Pipeline Design, Gas
Distribution infrastructure project execution, contractor management, Cost and
Budgeting, Sourcing, Tendering, authority management, health and safety
management

# Education

Stanford University Graduate School of Business

Management Development, Entrepreneurship/Entrepreneurial

Studies · (October 2015 - December 2015)

freeCodeCamp

Certificate, C# · (January 2021 - December 2021)

freeCodeCamp

Certificate, C++ · (January 2020 - December 2020)

**Udemy Alumni** 

Certificate, Python · (January 2019 - December 2019)

CodeAcademy

Certificate, JAVA · (January 2018 - December 2018)